https://ecokids.ca/privacy/

English | Français
EcoKids’ Privacy PolicyOur Privacy PhilosophyOur Privacy PrinciplesLimiting the Collection, Use and Disclosure of Your Personal InformationProtecting Your Personal InformationAddressing Your Inquiries and ConcernsUpdating this Privacy PolicyWebsites Governed by this Privacy PolicyGoverning Law
Our Privacy PhilosophyAt Earth Day Canada (1991) Inc., (“EcoKids”, “we” or “us”), we sincerely value the trust that you have placed in our organization. We have adopted this privacy policy (the “Policy”) to affirm our commitment to maintaining the accuracy, confidentiality, and security of your personal information collected in our mission to inspire children, adults, and communities to become environmental stewards through outdoor play and experiences.This Policy explains how we collect, use, disclose, and safeguard the personal information that you or a third party provide. Providing personal information or authorizing a third party to disclose personal information to us signifies your consent to EcoKids’ collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Policy.For the purposes of this Policy, “personal information” means information that can identify an individual directly or through other reasonably available means. The meaning of “personal information” shall be interpreted in a manner that conforms with the minimum requirements of applicable provincial and federal privacy legislation.You must be 18 years of age or older to consent to this Privacy Policy. For participants under 18 years of age, please be sure to obtain your parent’s or guardian’s permission before you send any information about yourself (your name, address, e-mail address, etc.) to us or anyone else over the Internet. We encourage parents to get involved with their children’s online usage and to be aware of the activities in which they are participating.Back to top ˆ
Our Privacy PrinciplesIdentifying Purposes and Obtaining Your ConsentWe identify the purposes for collecting your personal information at or before the time it is collected. We will not collect, use, or disclose your personal information without your informed consent, unless required or permitted to do so by law.At EcoKids, we collect, use, and disclose personal information about you so we can:Permit registration for, participation in, or application to an EcoKids program, campaign, initiative, event, competition, contest, award, fund/grant/scholarship, survey, or information alert;Process donations, including those made via a secure, third party provider;Deliver information, newsletters, alerts, announcements, awards, grants, prizes, guest passes/tickets or vouchers;Respond to requests for information, materials, or resources;Invite participation in or an application to an EcoKids program, campaign, initiative, event, competition, contest, award, fund/grant/scholarship, survey or fundraising effort;Aggregate and analyze data for statistical, evaluation, and reporting purposes;Manage and administer our relationships; andSatisfy requirements of the Canada Revenue Agency.We may also use your personal information to communicate with you for purposes consistent with the terms of this Policy.Should we require your information to fulfill a purpose that is not identified in this Policy, we will obtain your consent before proceeding.Back to top ˆ
Limiting the Collection, Use, and Disclosure of Your Personal InformationThe information we collectWe collect personal information by fair and lawful means and limit collection to that information which is necessary for the purposes identified in this Policy. The type of personal information that we may ask for includes:Signature (original and digital versions)NameAddressPostal codeEmail addressTelephone numberMobile telephone numberSocial media contactAge/Date of birthDonation information—e.g., date of gift, amount of gift, designation of gift, payment methodThe choice to provide us with your personal information, either directly or through a third party, is always yours. However, your decision to withhold particular information may limit our ability to provide you access to an EcoKids program, campaign, initiative, event, competition, contest, award, fund/grant/scholarship, survey, or information alert.How your information is collectedPersonal information may be collected in a number of ways, including: in person, over the phone, by mail, by fax, over the Internet, through mobile devices, through social media, and from third parties who you have authorized to disclose personal information to us.Web cookies are very small text files that are stored on your computer from a webpage to keep track of information about your browsing on that site. Through the use of web cookies, we may monitor the ads you see and the number of times you view them. The use of cookies also allows us to capture standard web traffic information, such as the time and date you visited our website, your IP address, and your browser information. In no circumstances do the cookies capture any information that can personally identify you.We make every reasonable effort to ensure that those third parties that disclose your personal information to us have first obtained your consent. If you believe that a third party has inappropriately disclosed your personal information to us, please contact that third party directly. If the third party does not sufficiently respond to your inquiries, please let us know immediately.Your personal information will only be used or disclosed in accordance with the purposes for which it was collected, unless you have otherwise consented or except where required or permitted by law.Disclosure to third partiesYou understand and agree that we may use your personal information and disclose your personal information to third parties that EcoKids engages to process donations, provide technical support, host website and online properties, and fulfill orders. Otherwise, we will only disclose your personal information to third parties if you have so consented or if required or permitted by law.The type of information we are legally required to disclose may relate to criminal investigations or government tax reporting requirements. In some instances, such as a legal proceeding or court order, we may also be required to disclose your personal information to authorities. Only the information specifically requested is disclosed and we take precautions to satisfy ourselves that the authorities that are making the disclosure request have legitimate grounds to do so.Your personal information may be disclosed in situations where we are legally permitted to do so, such as in the course of employing reasonable and legal methods to enforce your rights, or to investigate suspicion of unlawful activities. We may release certain personal information when we believe that such release is reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property, and safety of ourselves and others.Except as specifically provided for in this Policy, we do not disclose any personal information to third parties.Keeping your information accurateWe make every reasonable effort to keep your personal information as accurate, complete, and up-to-date as necessary. If desired, you may verify the accuracy and completeness of your personal information in our records.Despite our best efforts, errors sometimes do occur. Should you identify any incorrect or out-of-date information in your file, we will remedy any such errors on a timely basis. In the event that inaccurate information is mistakenly sent to a third party, we will communicate relevant changes to the third party where appropriate.Back to top ˆ
Protecting Your Personal InformationAccess to your information within EcoKidsAccess to private, sensitive, and confidential information, including your personal information, is restricted to authorized employees with legitimate business reasons. For example, when responding to participant enquiries, employees will need to access your information to verify your identity and to properly assist you.We require all of our employees to abide by EcoKids’ privacy standards. Our employees understand the importance of keeping your information private. For this reason, our employees are required to agree to confidentiality provisions that prohibit the disclosure of any participant information to unauthorized parties.Employees are strictly prohibited from accessing or disclosing personal information without authorization. All employees are expected to maintain the confidentiality of personal information at all times and failure to do so will result in appropriate disciplinary measures, including dismissal.Disposal and retentionExcept as otherwise permitted or required by law, your personal information will be retained for so long as is reasonably necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected. Disposal of personal information will be conducted securely.Safeguarding your informationTo ensure that your personal information is protected, we utilize security safeguards that are on par with the industry standard. We use modern technologies to help protect your confidential information. Our server environment and firewall infrastructure are well-maintained and our security practices are reviewed on a regular basis.We keep electronic participant files in a highly-secured environment with restricted access. Paper-based files are stored in locked filing cabinets to which access is also restricted. When you call our office staff, you will be required to verify your identity.Our online donation processing provider, CanadaHelps, uses Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to help ensure the safety and security of online donations. SSL technology enables encryption (scrambling) of sensitive information, including passwords and credit card numbers, during your online transactions. SSL protects and maintains the security of messages transmitted over the Internet. SSL scrambles your data into an unreadable format, preventing unauthorized access by others.Back to top ˆ
Addressing Your Inquiries and ConcernsWe are happy to provide you with a copy of this Policy and to discuss any of its content with you.Upon request, we will also inform you of: the type of personal information we have collected, how your personal information has been used, and any third parties to whom your personal information has been disclosed.Please direct all questions or enquiries about this Policy to:276 Roncesvalles AvenueToronto, Ontario M6R 2M2CanadaTelephone: 416-599-1991Fax: 416-599-3100Email: info@ecokids.caBack to top ˆ
Updating this Privacy PolicyAny changes to our privacy standards and information handling practices will be reflected in this Policy in a timely manner. EcoKids reserves the right to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this Policy at any time. Please check this page periodically for any modifications. To determine when this Policy was last updated, please refer to the modification date at the bottom of this Policy.Back to top ˆ
Websites Governed by this Privacy PolicyOur website (www.ecokids.ca) is governed by the provisions and practices stated in this Policy. Our website may contain links to third party sites that are not governed by this Policy. Although we endeavour to link only to sites that share our commitment to your privacy, please be aware that this Policy will no longer apply once you leave our website and that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of third-party sites. We therefore suggest that you closely examine the respective privacy policies of third-party websites to learn how they collect, use, and disclose your personal information.Back to top ˆ
Governing LawThis Policy and all related matters are governed solely by the laws of Ontario and the applicable federal laws of Canada.Last revised November 25, 2019.Back to top ˆ
